Christopher L. Cox

epistibrain.github.io

Contact
Information

(309) 472-4870

ChrisCoxMath@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research aims to broadly understand particle collisions and the corresponding billiard models. Using analytic and computational techniques, I am working to fill in a narrative beginning with a physically motivated geometric model, leading to the dynamics of the consequent billiards, and opening the door to more general statistical mechanical applications. Of particular interest are no-slip billiards, in which angular and linear momentum may be conservatively exchanged at collisions, and non-holonomic billiards, a related model arising from systems in which particles roll without sliding.

EMPLOYMENT

University of Delaware

Temporary Assistant Professor of Mathematics 2017-2018, 2020-present

Tarleton State University

Assistant Professor of Mathematics 2018-2020

Washington University in St. Louis

Postdoctoral Teaching Fellow 2016-2017

Illinois Central College

Professor of Mathematics 1998-2011

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis	Ph.D. in Mathematics	2016
Northwestern University	M.S. in Mathematics	1994

Williams College B.A. Cum Laude, with honors in Mathematics 1992

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- C. Cox, R. Feres, B. Zhao, *Rolling Systems and their Billiard Limits*, Regular and Chaotic Dynamics, 26 (2) 2021.
- T. Chumley, S. Cook, C. Cox, R. Feres, Rolling and no-slip bouncing in cylinders, Journal of Geometric Mechanics, 12 (1) 2020.
- C. Cox, R. Feres, H.-K. Zhang, Stability of periodic orbits of no-slip billiards, Nonlinearity, 31 (10), 2018, 4433-4471.
- C. Cox, R. Feres *No-slip billiards in dimension two*, Dynamical Systems, Ergodic Theory, and Probability: in Memory of Kolya Chernov, Contemporary Mathematics, vol. 698, Amer. Math. Soc., Providence, RI, 2017, 91-110.
- M. Correia, C. Cox, H.-K. Zhang, *Ergodicity in umbrella billiards*, New Horizons in Mathematical Physics, 1 (2), 2017, 56-67.
- C. Cox, R. Feres, Differential geometry of rigid bodies collisions and non-standard billiards, Discrete and Continuous Dynamical Systems A 36 (11), 2016, 6065-6099.